# Pete Moore

## Introduction

I have more than two decades' experience in the data industry, and I love helping organisations get the most from their data. I advise on data strategy. I code at expert level in R, Python and SQL. I have hands-on experience with the following machine learning and deep learning algorithms and methodologies: collaborative filtering, association rules, k-means, restricted Boltzmann machines, convolutional neural networks. I have composed code using the following deep learning platforms: Tensorflow, Keras, DL4J. This list however is not exhaustive because I strongly believe that the problem picks the platform and I am always willing to enhance my skill set accordingly. I'm constantly learning and refining my skills and am currently studying for an MSc Data Science at the University of Dundee (expected: Distinction).

## Experience

### Founder, Look at your Data Ltd - Jan 2017 - Dec 2018

Look at your Data delivered GDPR training to medium-sized groups of varied backgrounds, organisations and technical abilities.

### Non-executive Director, ManchesterSQL - Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

I was an inaugural member of Manchester SQL, a not-for-profit that organised the annual SQL Saturday conference and the monthly SQL Server User Group.

#### IT Director, Evolution Recruitment Solutions - Sep 2004 - Dec 2016

I was responsible for the data and IT at Evolution, a global recruitment company.

As IT Director I was responsible for: search algorithms across a corpus of over five million CV's; natural language processing (NLP), for example, to parse job descriptions from CVs; BI provision from consultant to board meeting; strategic IT direction of the company from infrastructure virtualisation to architecture of data estate. Responsible for internationalisation of sales practices and localisation of database. The voice of IT on the board. Often a counterpoint to sales wisdom.

#### IT Director, Evolution Recruitment Solutions - Jan 2012 - Dec 2016

I joined the board of Evolution in 2012 and the full board one year later. The first person ever to break into the inner circle having been a junior in the company.

- Virtualised Infrastructure: the organisation's international expansion entailed my supervision of an expansion in infrastructure. Using VMWare we virtualised the entire server estates and incorporated VDI's for peripatetic desktop users. Thus providing IaaS.
- Data warehouse
- Built a highly effective and collaborative team of twelve people who became Microsoft Gold Partners, an industry first
- Successfully introduced Kanban working practices across the organisation.

• MI as a habit: as a result of cross-enterprise management and careful stakeholder management, the business respected KPI's. The data warehouse behind these informed very important business decision. That is, data-driven operation as habit. This entailed the delivery of high level metrics such as profit to low level measures like call minutes.

### IT Manager, Evolution Recruitment Solutions – Jan 2007 - Dec 2011

After two years at Evolution my job title changed from Data- to IT- Manager. My main passion remained data, but the still small business need a comprehensive function and I was the obvious candidate to lead it.

This period began with the great recession, the opportunity create by this led to rapid UK-based expansion and culminated in a small single-brand, single-office, single-country, single-language company being turned into a multi-national, multiple brand enterprise.

- Migration from SQL Server 2000 to SQL Server 2008.
- MI as standard.
- Build and A/B testing of commercial websites.
- Establishment of scalable helpdesk function with replicable job units.
- Establishment of Data Management function.
- Pioneering of Database as a Service model (on SQL Server 2008) to allow a franchise-based business model.

## Data Manager, Evolution Recruitment Solutions - Sep 2004 - Dec 2006

My initial role at Evolution started when I was younger and more audacious. "If you can say it, I can code it" were the exact words that left my mouth. Whilst I never quite regretted them, it led to some interesting projects. Simply, no idea was too big and the projects we worked on then would one day be called "Data Science".

- Complex algorithms for CV matching and importing in SQL Server VB.Net and VB6.
- Wages automation in SQL Server and classic ASP.
- Elementary machine learning for email analysis.
- Establishment of Data Team plus basic support infrastructure.
- Introduction of per-consultant MI using SQL Server and ASP.

## Senior Data Manager, LBM - Aug 2002 - Oct 2003

LBM used data to drive direct marketing campaigns in the B2B sector.

### Senior Data Manager, LBM - Aug 2002 - Oct 2003

LBM demanded and if you didn't deliver you were out. I was in charge of the most important database in the company. Achieving this meant taking SQL Server and knowing the product inside out; going from apprentice to subject matter expert. If this seems unreasonable: it was. I didn't enjoy working at LBM, but I did learn a lot.

#### Business Objects Developer, InterAct Systems – Aug 1999 - Apr 2002

InterAct leveraged EPOS data to provide B2C offers through kiosk technology.

2018-10-19 2

## Business Applications Specialist, InterAct Systems – Apr 2001 - Apr 2002

Introduction to OLAP, ROLAP, Set-based programming using Business Objects Software.

## Data Analyst, InterAct Systems - Aug 1999 - Apr 2000

Providing, interpreting and automating reports for sales teams.

## **Hobbies**

In a lifetime of travel, I have scaled many of Europe's highest peaks, hiked fifty miles in a day for charity, and I have visited every US state apart from Hawaii. I even wrote a (bad) book about the latter.

I follow football, cricket, baseball and NFL. Sometimes to a level bordering on excessive. Ditto rock music, popular science and computing. I am genuinely passionate about my muse and don't differentiate studying about data from reading for pleasure.

In my spare time I like to perform stand-up and improv.

# Public speaking

As one who spends their spare time performing improv and stand-up comedy, it stands to reason that I like public speaking.

As a data professional I am fortunate enough to get invited to speak in locations as far afield as Ljubljana, Copenhagen but mostly Manchester. I have spoken in public on the facets of data that mean most to me: how to code well, how to communicate data by visualisation, to your boss and, fundamentally, how to keep this ethical.

# Volunteering

Table 1: Volunteering details

Position	Institution	Place	From	То
Non-executive Director	ManchesterSQL		Jan-2017	Dec-2017
Co-Organiser	Microsoft (PASS Chapter)		Jan-2017	Dec-2017
Owner	FC United		May-2005	Dec-2021

## Summer work

Table 2: Summer work details

Position	Institution	Place	From	То
Rides Assistant	Santa Cruz Beach Boardwalk	California	Jun-1998	Sep-1998
Games Assistant	Family Kingdom Amusement Park	South Carolina	Jun-1997	Sep-1997
Data Analyst	John Dickinson Stationery	Hertfordshire	Jun-1996	Sep-1996
Assistant Project Manager	Nat West	London	Jun-1995	$\operatorname{Sep-1995}$

2018-10-19 3

## Education

Table 3: Education details

Position	Institution	Place	From	То
MSc Data Science	University of Dundee	Angus	Jan-2017	Jan-2019
MSci Mathematical Physics (2:1)	University of Nottingham	Nottinghamshire	Oct-1995	Jun-1999
A-levels (AAAB)	Longdean School	Hertfordshire	Sep-1993	Jun-1995

# Opportunities fully visualised

# Community profile

- GitHub¹: https://github.com/databackwriter
- Blog: https://databackwriter.com
- Twitter: https://twitter.com/thedatabloke
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lookatmydata/
- StackOverflow: https://stackexchange.com/users/12936623/pete-moore

## CV edition information (internal use only)

IT Director CV issue 1002(1002) for Peter Moore

2018-10-19 4

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>for the R markdown that created this CV see: https://github.com/databackwriter/Pete-Moore---Data-Scientist---CV